So in the last module I showed you some ways of refactoring your reducers and I mentioned that these ways
Dolaysyla son modlde, redktrlerini yeniden yaplandrmann baz yollarn ve bu yollarn veya bu yntemlerin hepsinin
or these methods are all optional and they are, still I want to employ them here to clean up this reducer
istee bal olduunu ve yine de bu redktr temizlemek ve switch case ifadesini biraz
and make the switch case statement a little bit leaner I should say.
yapmak iin burada kullanmak istediklerini belirttim. sylemeliyim temizleyici.
So for example I'll add my updateObject convenience method which makes updating objects like we do
rnein, gncelleme nesnesi kolaylk yntemini ekleyeceim; bu, tm devlet iin yaptmz gibi nesneleri
for the entire state but then also the ingredients object here for example easier.
gncellemeyi, ancak daha sonra tm bileenleri Optik'e daha kolaylatryor.
For that, let's quickly add a new function and I'll add it in the store folder, utility.js, that's
Bunun iin hzl bir ekilde yeni bir ilev ekleyelim ve bunu, byle yazlmayan maaza klasr yardmc
not written like that,
programnda ekleyeceim.
that's correct.
Bu doru.
And now when there, I'll export a new constant which I'll name updateObject,
Ve hangi gncelleme nesnesi olarak adlandracam yeni bir sabit verildiinde.
it's an arrow function
Yani ok ilevi.
and in this function, I expect to get my old object and the updated properties or whatever you want to
Ve bu ileve eski nesne ve gncellenmi zellikleri ya da ne olursa olsun onu yeni
call it, new properties, whatever it is,
mlkler olarak adlandrmak isterim.
and in there, it's the same function as I wrote in the last modules. So in there,
Ve sonra orada yazdm son modlde olduu gibi ayn ilevi gryoruz.
I'll simply return a new javascript object,
Yeni bir javascript nesnesi dndrrm.
that's the whole idea behind that,
Bunun ardndaki tm fikir bu.
a new object, distribute the properties of the old object but then also distribute the properties of
datr, ancak nesne olarak gncellenmi zelliklerin zelliklerini de datmaktadr.
updated properties which should be an object too.
Yeni bir nesne eski nesnenin zelliklerini
Now I can use that updateObject function in my reducers
Artk redktrlerde gncelleme nesnesi ilevini kullanabilirim.
so I will import it at the top, import updateObject it's a named export so we need curly braces from
Bu yzden, ihracat adl stteki ie aktarm gncelleme nesnesine ie aktaracam ve yardmc dosyay yukarya karmamz
moving up the utility file
iin quali parantezlerine ihtiyacmz var.
and now I can call updateObject whenever I have code like this, where I distribute some props.
Ve imdi, baz sahne datm yaptmda byle bir kod bulunduunda gncelleme nesnesini aracam.
So in this case here, I'll have my updatedIngredients first, that will now be a call to updateObject
Bu durumda burada gncel maddelerim ncelikle devlet maddesinden Sodhi'nin eski malzemelerinden
where I pass state.ingredient, so the old ingredients,
geerek gncelleme nesnesine ar yapacak.
so now I'm replicating this part and where I pass my new ingredients, this part.
imdi bu ksm tekrar ediyorum ve yeni malzemelerimi bu blmde geiyorum.
So here I'll create my, a new constant just to have it split up over multiple lines and not set all of
Dolaysyla hepsi benim yeni konseptimi sadece birden fazla satra ayrlmak iin yaratyor ve hepsini tek bir ifade
that into one expression,
haline getirmek iin deil.
so here I'll have my updatedIngredient,
Bylece burada gncellenmi ieriim olacak.
that should be a javascript object where I have just that key value pair, the dynamic name of the ingredient
yle ki sadece l anahtar deeri iftinin dinamik adn ve artan gncellenmi deeri
and then the updated value which is incremented and then I'll pass this updatedIngredient as a second
ve daha sonra tm gemii Apptd nesnesine ikinci bir argman olarak gncelletiren bir
argument to updateObject
Java nesnesi olmal.
and it has to be an object, updatedIngredient has to be an object because this is what the utility
Ve bu gncellenmi bir maddenin bir nesne olmas gereken bir nesne olmal, nk bu, fayda
function expects
fonksiyonunun bekledii ey.
otherwise this won't work as expected.
Aksi halde beklendii gibi almaz.
So with that, I have the updatedIngredients,
Bu yzden gncellenmi malzemeler ieriyor.
this is what I assign to ingredients now
te imdi malzemelere atadm ey bu.
but of course, the whole idea is that I also replace this part.
Fakat elbette btn fikir, bu blm her zaman deitirdiimdir.
So I'll create a new constant which I'll name updatedState
Bylece gncellenmi durumu belirten yeni bir ierik oluturursunuz.
maybe, this should be a javascript object where I now have my ingredients and total price, like that.
Belki de bu imdi bir javascript nesnesi olmal, burada ieriklerim ve bunun gibi toplam fiyatm var.
And in the end here, I can therefore then call updateObject, this and pass the old state which is the
Sonunda buradan gncelleme nesnesini arabilir ve gncellemek istediim Optik olduu eski durumu geebilirim.
object I want to update, I want to return here and pass the updated state.
Buraya dnmek ve gncellenmi durumu geirmek istiyorum.
So still a lot of lines, a little bit more structured and using that utility function
Hl bir sr izgi biraz daha yaplandrlm ve o fayda fonksiyonunu kullanyor.
and I just wanted to show how to implement this,
Ve ben sadece bunun nasl uygulanacan gstermek istedim.
we could have squeezed all of that into one line but that would have been a bit hard to follow along,
Bunlarn hepsini tek bir sraya skm olabilirdik, ancak takip etmek biraz zordu.
that is why I wrote it over multiple lines.
Bu yzden birden fazla satra yazdm.
So now I'll copy all that code because when we remove ingredient, it's essentially the same story
Bu yzden btn kodlar kopyalayacam nk ierii kaldrdmzda temelde
but there of course, the difference is that we need to decrement our ingredient by one.
ayn hikaye ama elbette fark, bileenimizi birer birer azaltmamz gerektiidir.
And even though it's in a switch case statement, it does like the fact that I reassign a constant here,
Ve switch case deyiminde olmasna ramen burada bir sabitin yeniden atanmas bu
doesn't recognize that I can't reach this code.
koda ulaamayacam tanmyor gibi grnyor.
So what I'll do is I'll simply rename these constants,
Bu yzden, yapacam basite bu Konstanslar yeniden adlandrmaktr.
not ideal but unfortunately has to be done, updatedSt
deal deil fakat ne yazk ki gncellenmi olarak yaplmaldr.
maybe, so this is just again necessary due to the fact that the IDE doesn't pick up these constant, constants
Belki de bu, DS'nin sabit sabitlerle deitirilemeyecei gereinden dolay
can never be reassigned.
tekrar gereklidir.
So with that, let's use updatedIngredients
Bu yzden gncellenmi ierikleri kullanalm.
here, so this new constant I just created and updatedIng here and then updatedState, down there.
te yeni oluturduum ve gncellediim yeni sabit, burada kaldm gncellendi.
Now for setIngredients, it's a bit easier, there
imdi ayarlanm malzemeler iin buras biraz daha kolaydr.
I also want to return a call to updateObject, so to the function we're importing,
Ayrca, ie aktarldmz ileve nesne gncelleme ars da vermek istiyorum.
I pass state of course and the second argument should be a javascript object where I now just copy
Tabii ki durumdan getim ve ikinci argman, daha nce de bu yeni nesneye aktardm
all the code I previously also passed to this new object.
tm kodu kopyaladm bir javascript nesnesi olmaldr.
So now I'm using my utility function here too to update the state and the same of course down here for
imdi, fayda ilevi ile durumu gncellemek iin burada kullanyorum ve burada
the error, there
ayn hata var.
I also want to call updateState, like this, updateObject I mean.
Ben de bu gncelleme nesnesi gibi gncelleme durumu armak istiyorum.
So as always updateObject
Bylece her zaman gncellenir.
where I pass the state and then object where I set error to true, like this.
Nesnenin tecavz edilmesi durumu belirtmeli ve daha sonra Optik, burada sz geen bir hata veya bunun gibi dorudur.
So that is the ingredient reducer updated with our utility function,
Kullandmz bileen, fayda fonksiyonumuzla gncelleniyor.
let's now do the same for that order reducer.
imdi de bu emir redktr iin ayn eyi yapalm.
There I'll also import as a named export updateObject from the utility file which we can find one level
Ayrca, tm redktr klasrnn stnde bir dzey bulabileceiniz ve hibir optik gncelleme gerektirmeyen yardmc programdan adlandrlm bir
above our reducers folder and now I'll use updateObject here too.
ihracat gncelleme nesnesi olarak ithalat da yaplmaktadr.
So I'll return updateObject, pass the state and pass a javascript object where purchased is set to false,
Yani duruma geirilen bir gncelleme nesnesi ve bir javascript nesnesi geildiinde kovaland false olur.
you can remove this code here, the same here,
Bu kodu daha sonra buradan kaldrabilirsiniz.
updateObject pass the state and an object where we set loading to false, like this,
Gncelleme nesnesi, byle bir false deerine yklenen bir nesneyi durumuna geirir.
remove that code.
Bu kodu kaldrn.
And also when we get success case here, there we of course also want to update an object,
Ve baar elde ettiimizde orada olduunuzu tabii ki tm bir nesneyi gncellemek istiyor.
so here I will update an object where I pass the state of course and then all these things here as properties
Yani burada bir nesneyi tabii ki durumdan sonra gncelleyeceim ve daha sonra bir javascript nesnesinin zellikleri bundan sonra koddan kurtulabilecei
of a javascript object, can get rid of the code thereafter.
iin btn bu eyleri burada gncelleyeceim.
And of course we update another object here, here
Ve elbette burada Optik numarasn gncelliyoruz burada.
newOrder,
Yeni sipari.
there we also update an object,
Orada bir nesneyi de gncelliyoruz.
we get the action order data here as an object
D alyoruz S. Buraya bir nesne olarak sipari veri.
and I want to pass a new property to it, the id which should be action order ID and with that, I can get
Ve eylem emri kimlii olmas gereken yeni kimlik belgesine kimlii gemek istiyorum ve
rid of this code here.
bu koddan kurtulamyorum.
So now we got this using our updateObject function too
imdi bunu optik fonksiyonumuzdaki uygulamalarmz kullanarak aldk.
and we're nearing the end,
Ve biz sonuna yaklayoruz.
let's also do this for purchaseBurger, burger fail, fail, have the state here, loading set to false.
Ayrca satn almak iin bunu yapalm Forgan Berger FAIL FAIL durumu burada yanl ayarlar yklemelisiniz.
So there also using the updateObject function and I'll quickly duplicate this for fetch order start
Bu nedenle gncelleme Optik ilevini kullanyorlar ve veya bugn burada getirmeleri iin hzl bir
except for data here,
ekilde oaltyorlar.
as you see I want to set loading to true and for fetchOrderSuccess, I'll call updateObject also
Grdnz gibi, yklemeyi true olarak ayarlamak ve siparileri getirmek iin baary aracam, ayrca nesneye devredeceim
pass the state and then I'll have orders and loading set to false as properties which I want to pass
ve sonra da tmnn emir aldklarn ve bir kez bir javascript nesnesi gibi aktardnz zellikler
as a javascript object, like that.
olarak false olarak ayarlanmasn ykleyeceklerini hatrlatacam. syledi.
And now the last updateObject called down there for fetch orders fail,
Ve imdi fetch siparileri iin orada arlan son gncelleme nesnesi baarsz.
there I'll pass the existing state which is to be updated and an object where I set loading to false.
Korkun gncellenecek olan mevcut durumu ve tm zelletirmeleri yanl yklemek iin geti.
Again all of that is optional
Yine tm bunlar istee baldr.
but it does re-use that utility function
Ama fayda fonksiyonunu drr.
and if you ever were to change the logic you use for updating an object, you only have to do it in one
Ve herhangi bir nesneyi gncellemek iin kullandnz mant deitirirseniz, yalnzca tek bir
place.
yerde yapmanz yeterlidir.
Now let's quickly see if that all works, loading does work,
imdi hzl bir ekilde yklenimin tmnn ie yarayp yaramadn greceiz.
managing the burger does seem to work
Bir burger ynetmek ie yaryor gibi grnyor.
so that is all good, I guess.
Sanrm btn bunlar iyi.
Let's quickly go to the checkout page
Hzla deme sayfasna gidelim.
so that's that's looking good,
Bu yzden bu iyi grnyor.
seems to work.
e yaryor gibi grnyor.
What else can we do?
Baka ne yapabiliriz.
Let's have a look in the next lecture.
Bir sonraki konferansa bir gz atalm.